okay just want to film a quick video
about glute strength
uh this is a very important talk for the
strength and conditioning field the
sport specific training field
um a lot of people think oh i'll just do
squats
my glutes will be strong well strength
is kind of range
specific so you can't just do a squat
and expect
to have your glutes strong from you know
from every vector or
in every range of motion so in a squat
the glutes work mostly down here up to
about right here
and then from here up it's not you know
not much tension on the glutes so when
you do
so if i were to just do squats i would
have good glute strength down low
but i i leave some room on the table up
high
and you do a deadlift kind of same thing
um glutes are working real hard from
here to here and then
they lock it out but like right up top
here
you know it's mainly the erector spinae
holding holding
you up right here so at the neutral hip
position
squats and deadlifts leave a little bit
of room on my table
when you do a barbell look bridge or a
hip thrust
the hardest part is right here at
neutral so right here is the hardest
part for your glutes
same with a you know
a barbell hip thrust um
hardest part right up top for the glitch
so right here would be the hardest part
so where does this range of hip strength
correspond to
when it comes to sports when you do a
vertical jump
you need hip strength right here but
right here you don't need any hip
strength it would send you
too far forward and you know screw up
your
your um coordination and balance but
when you sprint
your leg is cycling and i'm talking
about max feet spring when you're
upright running as fast as you can
your left leg cycles around touches down
around eight inches in front of your
body absorbs breaking forces
and then propels you forward
so this motion here
when the foot touches down in a sprint
that's when you get the most glute
activation
that's when your glute really has to
absorb
power and then propel you forward so
at this range of motion you need to do
the hip thrust
because that's where you have that added
glute strength enhancing strength from
that exact position
so i hope you find this video useful
check my blog out
at wreck interest.wordpress.com